# **BHARATH KANNAN**

Birmingham, United Kingdom

Phone: +44-1234-567-890 | Email: <u>bazkannan96@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/bharath-kannan/ | Website: https://bazkannan.com/

#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

A diligent, collaborative, and multi-disciplinary designer with over 3 years of experience in the creative industry and agile environments, including FTSE 100 experience. Notable achievements include designing, optimising, and delivering UX of the company-wide chatbot application using various programmes including Figma and Adobe Creative Cloud (XD, Photoshop, After Effects, InDesign). Delivered chatbot application improvements to enable better UX and attained 35% better customer reception. Additionally, improved user journey for over 500,000 customers on the mobile banking app, and reduced the abandonment rate by over 60%. Currently studying UI/UX Design bootcamp at the University of Birmingham.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Technical: Wordpress, Elementor, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Graphic Design: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign
Film and Motion Graphics: Adobe After Effects, Apple Motion, Flnal Cut Pro

UI/UX: Figma, FIGJAM, Adobe XD, Microsoft Visio

## **PROJECTS**

#### Mobile Travel App

https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1cfTEPqNOKwuPImqBUzN-LH0y7Q1Xj3v3dKx66KPWCDI/edit?usp=drive\_link

- The creation of a travel app for mobile phone devices that address the common frustrations of frequent travellers.
- Conducted user research through a combination of user interviews, data synthesis with affinity diagrams and the implementation of iOS components to design and create a mobile prototype.
- Figma, FIGJAM, Google Forms, Adobe Photoshop

# **Digital Oyster Card**

https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1sW3uLgaijSo11Zt7trWDx2All\_xHqBM\_6i6CrWGa5k4/edit?usp=drive\_link

- Creating a seamless commuting experience for TFL travellers living in London and incentivising them to switch to Oyster Cards from Contactless payments.
- Led and collaborated with a team to conduct user research on London travellers and produce mobile prototypes for the proposed solution of digitalised Oyster Cards.
- Figma, FIGJAM, Google Forms, Adobe Photoshop

#### **NSA Government Web Redesign**

https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1\_w5lt8Z9n9yG99w-yJvTW0pbtb9452CKGdJ05g7z0Ok/edit?usp=drive\_link

- Redesigning an existing government website that aims to improve the user experience of visitors seeking to acquire information about the National Security Agency (NSA).
- Conducted heuristic evaluation of the existing government website for NSA along with user interviews. Also created a rebranded style guide and a responsive web and mobile prototype for website redesign.
- Figma, FIGJAM, Adobe Photoshop

# SANE Website Redesign

 $\frac{https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1TIVcIVDdKnazgDcOzxuv5KBQxN\_DXHNuw262xRqLQFo/edit?usp=drive\_link}{}$ 

- Redesigning an existing non-profit organisation website that intends to target users who face challenges with mental health.
- Led and collaborated with a team to conduct user research on users who face challenges with mental health and created rebranded logo, style guide and responsive web and mobile prototype
- Figma, FIGJAM, CSS Bootstrap, Google Forms, Adobe Photoshop

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Conversation Engineer & Design - January 2021 - December 2023 - Lloyd's Banking Group, London, UK

- Successfully designed, built, tested, and optimised the UX of the chatbot application using a combination of Microsoft Visio, IBM Watson Assistant, JIRA and Figma programmes and delivered companywide chatbot applications for over 3 million customers.
- Led and worked with 50 business stakeholders, designers, copywriters, and conversation analysts to assess the customer requirements and delivered a high quality UX.
- Led on and delivered improvements for applications once deployed live to enable better UX and attained 35% better customer reception. Led UX improvement sprints while working with a team of 12 mobile messaging engineers, managed and created JIRA tickets, ensured application improvements actions were completed to time, delivery and budget and provided technical expertise to the team. The outcome was improvements for over 100 customer journeys through analysis of 500 customer conversations.

Graduate Technology Consultant – April 2020 – December 2020 – FDM Group, Birmingham, UK

- Successfully completed a 10 week training programme in the graduate scheme for FDM which
  included advanced levels modules for Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and SQL. Additionally
  delivered Website design using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Collaboratively worked with a team of 10 technology consultants and led the design workstream, successfully producing a collection of wireframe designs using Adobe Illustrator and successfully sought buy-in from clients.

Product & Business Development Placement – June 2017 – July 2017 – Unidos Financial Services Inc., New York, USA

 Delivered Quality Assurance, User Acceptance Testing, Optimisation of the Customer Support and Content Development to support successful completion and launch of high quality Mobile application for 500,000 customers across Latin America.

- Completed over 100 testing scenarios and resolved over 100 errors using Backend UI databases and Microsoft Excel.
- Responsible for and completed User Acceptance testing, which entailed managing over 50 major user requirements processes to ensure they were met, and created user requirements reports for Senior Product Lead and Senior Vice President of Product Strategy and Development.
- Delivered Customer Service improvements by 30%, as measured by our feedback reporting, through training customer contact teams using live customer call training and feedback reports.
- Supported customer registration activity, whilst working collaboratively with 20 team members and approved over 200 applications using strict policy criterion and risk mechanisms.

#### **EDUCATION**

2024 - Present

# University of Birmingham, EDX

 UI/UX Design Bootcamp. Modules include: Introduction to User Experience (UX), User Interface (UI), Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Information Architecture, Usability Testing, Interaction Design, Prototyping and Wireframing, Mobile and Responsive Design, Visual Communication, User Research and Design Thinking

2018 - 2019

# University of Birmingham

 MSc (Hons) Computer Science (1 Year Conversation Course) – PASS. Modules included: Human Computer Interaction, Software Engineering and Final Project using

Adobe XD, JavaScript and React Native

2015 - 2018

# University of Birmingham

BSc (Hons) Economics (2:2)

2013 - 2015

# King Edward VI Aston, Birmingham

A-levels - Mathematics (A), Chemistry (A), Economics (A)

2008 - 2013

# Priory School, Birmingham

• GCSEs – 8A\* - B, including B in English